<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>International Blood/Plasma News</title>
    <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
    <description>Latest news and updates from International Blood/Plasma News, April 2024 issue.</description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
    <generator>Custom RSS Feed Generator</generator>

    <item>
      <title>U.S. FDA approves PFIZER’S BEQVEZ for moderate to severe hemophilia B</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article1</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>The U.S. FDA has approved PFIZER’S BEQVEZ (fidanacogene elaparvovec-dzkt), a one-time gene therapy for the treatment of adults with moderate to severe hemophilia B who:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Currently use factor IX prophylaxis therapy, or</li>
          <li>Have current or historical life-threatening hemorrhage, or</li>
          <li>Have repeated, serious spontaneous bleeding episodes, and</li>
          <li>Do not have neutralizing antibodies to adeno-associated virus serotype Rh74var (AAVRh74var) capsid as detected by an FDA-approved test.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>U.S. marketing approval was based on safety and efficacy results from the open-label, single-arm, Phase 3 BENEGENE-2 study, which evaluated BEQVEZ in adult male participants (ages 18 to 65 years) with moderately severe to severe hemophilia B, defined as factor IX circulating activity of 2% or less. Forty-five participants received a single intravenous infusion of BEQVEZ at a dose of 5 x 1011 vg/kg of body weight.</p>
        <p>A mean annualized bleeding rate (ABR) of 2.5 was observed during the BEQVEZ efficacy evaluation period between week 12 and data cutoff (median of 1.8 years of follow-up), compared to a mean ABR of 4.5 during the minimum six-month lead-in pre-treatment period; median ABRs were respectively zero (range of 0 to 19) and 1.3 (range of 0 to 53.9) during the prophylaxis pre-treatment period.</p>
        <p>Bleeding events were eliminated in 60% of patients following treatment with BEQVEZ, compared to 29% during the prophylaxis pre-treatment period. BEQVEZ was generally well-tolerated, with no reported serious adverse events. Study participants will be followed for up to a total of 15 years, including six years in the BENEGENE-2 study, and an additional nine years as part of a separate Phase 3 study.</p>
        <p>Pfizer has set a U.S. list price of $3.5 million per single dose for BEQVEZ therapy, matching the price set by CSL BEHRING for its hemophilia B gene therapy, HEMGENIX (etranacogene dezaparvovec-drlb) when it was approved by the U.S. FDA in November 2022. Pfizer licensed BEQVEZ from SPARK THERAPEUTICS in December 2014, agreeing to assume responsibility for pivotal studies, regulatory activities, and potential global commercialization of this gene therapy. CSL licensed the exclusive global rights to commercialize HEMGENIX from uniQure in May 2021.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>UK MHRA expands approval of TAKEDA’S TAKHZYRO for hereditary angioedema</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article2</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>The UK’s Medicines and Healthcare Products Regulatory Agency (MHRA) has expanded its approval of TAKEDA’S TAKHZYRO (lanadelumab) to prevent recurrent attacks of hereditary angioedema (HAE) to include patients aged two to less than 12 years. TAKHZYRO is now the first long-term prophylactic treatment for HAE that is available in the UK for children aged two to under six years.</p>
        <p>“The announcement that children under 12 now have access to this treatment option will be looked back on as a huge milestone for the HAE community,” said HAE UK chief executive officer Angela Metcalfe.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>UK MHRA approves TAKEDA’S HyQvia for chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy (CIDP)</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article3</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Separately, the UK’s MHRA has approved TAKEDA’S HyQvia (Immune Globulin Infusion 10% [Human] with Recombinant Human Hyaluronidase) for use by patients of all ages with chronic inflammatory demyelinating polyneuropathy (CIDP) following stabilization with intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) therapy. HyQvia is already approved in the UK as an immunoglobulin G (IgG) replacement therapy for qualifying patients with primary and secondary immunodeficiency disorders.</p>
        <p>This approval follows shortly on similar approvals of HyQvia as maintenance therapy for adult CIDP patients in the U.S. and the European Union in January.</p>
        <p>As many as 650 people are diagnosed with CIDP each year in the UK, according to Guillain-Barré and Associated Inflammatory Neuropathies (GAIN) chief executive officer Rich Collins, who welcomed this additional treatment option for people impacted by this autoimmune neurological disorder.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>BioMarin Pharmaceutical faces challenges with ROCTAVIAN gene therapy reimbursement and market access</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article4</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>BioMarin Pharmaceutical reported that reimbursement and market access challenges have “continued to impact the ability of interested patients to receive ROCTAVIAN [hemophilia A gene therapy]” in the three countries to date – the U.S., Germany and Italy – where pricing and reimbursement have been established. ROCTAVIAN generated just $800,000 in revenue in the first quarter ended March 31, all attributable to a single patient in Italy who received the gene therapy days after the quarter end.</p>
        <p>“Aligning the required steps leading to patient treatment continues to pose different challenges,” a senior a senior company official acknowledged on an investor conference call. “While the national German price was established and published in December , sub-insurers inserted new barriers to reimbursement,” and in the U.S., “the complexity of local site reimbursement contracting continues to be an obstacle,” he added.</p>
        <p>BioMarin plans to communicate “evaluation criteria” it will apply to decide on the disposition of ROCTAVIAN at an upcoming investor event scheduled in September. While hopeful for a meaningful ramp-up in uptake of the gene therapy, BioMarin says it is prepared to either (1) “right-size” ROCTAVIAN-related R&D, medical affairs and commercialization activity if it concludes that there is a lower potential uptake, or (2) remove ROCTAVIAN from its product portfolio and divest this asset.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>MEDEXUS PHARMACEUTICALS expands IXINITY indication for pediatric hemophilia B</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article5</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>MEDEXUS PHARMACEUTICALS announced that the U.S. FDA has approved its supplemental Biologics License Application (sBLA) for IXINITY (Coagulation Factor IX [Recombinant]), expanding its labeled indication to include on-demand, prophylactic and perioperative treatment of pediatric patients under 12 years of age with hemophilia B. Previously, IXINITY was indicated for these clinical applications only in adults and children ≥12 years of age.</p>
        <p>This expanded indication was based on results from a Phase 3/4 study, which evaluated the pharmacokinetics, safety and efficacy of IXINITY as a prophylactic treatment in previously treated pediatric patients under 12 years of age with severe or moderately severe hemophilia B.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>AVENACY launches generic Desmopressin Acetate for Injection in U.S.</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article6</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>AVENACY announced that it has launched Desmopressin Acetate for Injection in the U.S. as a therapeutic equivalent generic for FERRING PHARMACEUTICALS’ DDAVP for Injection (Desmopressin Acetate). It will be supplied by the Illinois-based specialty pharmaceutical company in two presentations: 4 mcg per 1 mL single-dose vials, and 40 mcg per 10 mL multiple-dose vials.</p>
        <p>U.S. sales of Desmopressin Acetate for Injection totaled approximately $39 million for the 12 months ending in June 2023. The product is indicated for:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>Hemophilia A with factor VIII coagulant activity levels greater than 5% without factor VIII antibodies to (1) maintain hemostasis during surgical procedures and postoperatively and (2) reduce bleeding with episodes of spontaneous or traumatic injuries such as hemarthroses, intramuscular hematomas, or mucosal bleeding.</li>
          <li>Mild to moderate von Willebrand disease (type I) with factor VIII levels greater than 5% for the same clinical purposes.</li>
          <li>Antidiuretic replacement therapy in the management of central (cranial) diabetes insipidus and for the management of the temporary polyuria and polydipsia following head trauma or surgery in the pituitary region.</li>
        </ul>
        <p>Other generic alternatives to DDAVP are also available in the U.S., including injectable desmopressin acetate products from DR REDDYS and GLAND PHARMA, respectively approved in August 2022 and March 2023.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Takeda’s ADZYNMA approved in Japan for congenital thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (cTTP)</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article7</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>TAKEDA announced that the Japanese Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare has approved the use of ADZYNMA (apadamtase alfa/cinaxadamtase alfa) for prophylactic and on-demand treatment of congenital thrombotic thrombocytopenic purpura (cTTP), for individuals 12 years of age and older. ADZYNMA is the first and only approved recombinant ADAMTS13 protein to address an unmet need in people with cTTP for ADAMTS13 enzyme replacement.</p>
        <p>The approval was supported by an interim analysis of efficacy, pharmacokinetic, safety and tolerability data from a randomized, controlled, open-label, crossover Phase 3 trial in cTTP patients ages 12 to 68 years, inclusive of long-term safety and efficacy data from a continuation study.</p>
        <p>No study patient experienced an acute TTP event while receiving ADZYNMA prophylactic treatment (n=37); there was one acute TTP event in a patient receiving plasma-based therapies (n=38) during the Phase 3 study-controlled comparison periods 1 and 2. Treatment-emergent adverse events (TEAEs) were reported in 10.3% of patients receiving ADZYNMA compared to 50% of patients receiving conventional plasma-based therapy.</p>
        <p>ADZYNMA also received marketing approval in the U.S. in December 2023, for prophylactic and on-demand treatment of adult and pediatric patients with this ultra-rare blood clotting disorder.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>CRISPR-based gene therapy CASGEVY shows high efficacy in sickle cell disease and transfusion-dependent beta-thalassemia</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article8</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>VERTEX PHARMACEUTICALS’ CRISPR-based gene-editing therapy CASGEVY (exagamglogene autotemcel [exa-cel]) eliminated vaso-occlusive crises (VOCs) in 97% of evaluable adolescent and adult patients with sickle cell disease (SCD), according to results from a Phase 3, single-group, open-label study.</p>
        <p>Developed in collaboration with the Swiss-based biotechnology firm CRISPR THERAPEUTICS, CASGEVY received U.S. FDA marketing approval for the treatment of SCD patients 12 years of age and older with recurrent VOCs in December 2023. An estimated 16,000 U.S. SCD patients are believed to be potential candidates for this novel, first-in-class gene editing therapy.</p>
        <p>Following myeloablative conditioning with busulfan, CASGEVY was administered to a total of 44 patients 12 to 35 years of age who had a history of at least two severe VOCs in each of the two years before screening. Of the 30 patients who had sufficient follow-up to be evaluated, 29 (97%; 95% confidence interval [CI], 83 to 100%) were free from VOCs for at least 12 consecutive months. All 30 patients were free from hospitalizations for VOCs for at least 12 consecutive months.</p>
        <p>CASGEVY is a nonviral cell therapy designed to reactivate fetal hemoglobin synthesis by means of ex vivo clustered regularly interspaced short palindromic repeats (CRISPR)-Cas9 gene editing of autologous CD34+ hematopoietic stem and progenitor cells at the erythroid-specific enhancer region of BCL11A. Complete findings from this study are published in the April 24 online issue of the New England Journal of Medicine.</p>
        <p>In a separate open-label, single-group, Phase 3 study in patients 12 to 35 years of age with transfusion-dependent b-thalassemia and selected genotypes, a single treatment with CASGEVY resulted in transfusion independence in 32 (91%) of the 35 patients with sufficient follow-up data for evaluation, according to a report by the CLIMB THAL-111 Study Group in the April 24 online issue of the New England Journal of Medicine.</p>
        <p>During transfusion independence, the mean total hemoglobin level was 13.1 g/dL, including a mean fetal hemoglobin level of 11.9 g/dL. As with the Phase 3 trial co-published in NEJM in patients with sickle cell disease and a history of recurrent vaso-occlusive crises, the safety profile of CASGEVY was generally consistent with that of pre-treatment myeloablative busulfan conditioning and autologous hematopoietic stem cell and progenitor cell transplantation; no deaths or cancers occurred.</p>
        <p>Manufacturer and supplier VERTEX PHARMACEUTICALS estimates that approximately 1,000 patients in the U.S. 12 years of age and older may be eligible for one-time CASGEVY therapy.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>ALEXION PHARMACEUTICALS’ VOYDEYA approved for extravascular hemolysis in PNH</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article9</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>ALEXION PHARMACEUTICALS announced the U.S. approval of VOYDEYA (danicopan), a first-in-class oral, Factor D inhibitor, as add-on therapy to its approved C5 inhibitors ULTOMIRIS (ravulizumab) or SOLIRIS (eculizumab) for the treatment of extravascular hemolysis (EVH) in adults with paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria (PNH). Approximately 10-20% of patients with PNH experience clinically significant EVH while treated with a C5 inhibitor.</p>
        <p>VOYDEYA was approved based on positive results from the double-blind, randomized, Phase 3 ALPHA trial, results of which were published in the December 2023 issue of The Lancet Haematology.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>South Korean start-up ArtBlood secures investment for 'Cell-Based Artificial Blood' development</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article10</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>A South Korean biotechnology start-up called ArtBlood announced that it has secured an investment of 6.5 billion won ($4.8 million) from multiple investors to advance development of extracorporeal red blood cell production, using highly proliferative cell lines and proprietary technology that mimics the bone marrow’s blood production process. This follows a grant of 4.7 billion won ($3.5 million) awarded in 2023 by South Korea’s Ministry of Health and Welfare to develop “Cell-Based Artificial Blood”.</p>
        <p>Founded by Prof. Baek Eun Jung at Hanyang University, ArtBlood claims that its hematopoietic cell lines are capable of mass-producing precursor red blood cells with normal chromosomes, which it has brand named BioBlood. “BioBlood is a cell-based blood product of the highest quality with diverse applications, Prof. Jung said in a public statement. “Through commercialization, it will contribute to the health and welfare of humanity”.</p>
        <p>According to a report in the Korea Economic Daily, BioBlood has the potential to serve as an “alternative solution to blood shortages, with advantages such as transfusion compatibility regardless of blood type, prevention of infection risks associated with direct blood transfusion, and longer viability in vitro than donated blood”.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>CSL BEHRING’S HEMGENIX shows durable disease correction in hemophilia B patients</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article11</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>An updated analysis of the Phase 3 HOPE-B trial evaluating CSL BEHRING’S HEMGENIX (etranacogene dezaparvovec) gene therapy in adult males with hemophilia B found that it provided durable disease correction throughout the 24 months after administration.</p>
        <p>Fifty-four adult males with severe or moderately severe disease who received a single intravenous infusion of HEMGENIX were followed for a median of 26.5 months, after a median lead-in period of 7.1 months. The mean adjusted annualized bleeding rate (ABR) was significantly reduced from 4.18 to 1.51 (p = 0.0002) for all bleeds, and from 3.65 to 0.99 (p = 0.0001) for factor IX-treated bleeds.</p>
        <p>During each six-month period after gene therapy, at least 67% of study participants experienced no bleeding (36 of 54 patients during months 0-6 and stable thereafter), compared with 14 (26%) of 54 during the lead-in period. One participant (2%) had factor IX activity of less than 5%, whereas 18 (33%) had factor IX activity exceeding 40%, with mean factor IX activity stable and sustained at 36.7% (standard deviation, 19.0%). Fifty-two of 54 participants remained free of factor IX prophylaxis at month 24.</p>
        <p>No new safety concerns were identified and no treatment-related serious adverse events occurred. “Etranacogene dezaparvovec provides a safe and effective therapeutic option for patients with severe or moderately severe hemophilia B,” the HOPE-B investigators concluded. Complete findings are published in the April 2024 issue of The Lancet Haematology.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Study identifies substantial autoantibodies in pooled plasma and IVIG, cautioning clinicians</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article12</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>In what they believe to be the first study of its kind, researchers at JAPAN BLOOD PRODUCTS ORGANIZATION identified substantial titers of three specific autoantibodies in both pooled plasma and intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG), which are known to be present and in patients with Hashimoto’s thyroiditis, Graves’ disease and Sjögren’s syndrome.</p>
        <p>Of 18 autoantibody varieties explored in five different sets of pooled plasma used to produce an unidentified commercial Japanese IVIG product, 12 were below the minimum level of detection. Levels of three of six other autoantibodies – thyroid stimulating antibody (TSAb), anti-lupus anticoagulant (LA) antibody and antibody against Sjögren’s syndrome-related antigen B – were within the normal reference range in pooled plasma samples. In contrast, titers of anti-Tg, anti-TPO and anti-SS-A antibodies in these five pooled plasma samples were well above their reference ranges.</p>
        <p>Substantial titers of these three autoantibodies were also detected in all five production lots of the Japanese IVIG product; as a result of the IgG purification process, all three were concentrated roughly 10-fold or more than their levels in pooled plasma. Similar titers of anti-Tg and anti-TPO antibody were detected as well in a single production lot of an unidentified U.S. IVIG product; anti-SS-A antibody was also detected, albeit at a lower titer.</p>
        <p>“Clinicians should keep in mind that IVIGs contain several autoantibodies and that their infusion can produce false-positive serology results,” the study investigators concluded. “To establish an accurate diagnosis, serological tests must be carefully interpreted and clinical symptoms should be more purposefully considered if patients are receiving IVIG therapy.” Their complete findings appear in the April 2024 issue of Transfusion.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>CSL112 fails to meet primary efficacy endpoint in acute myocardial infarction trial</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article13</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Two months after CSL BEHRING announced that its investigational human plasma-derived apolipoprotein A-I product (CSL112) failed to meet its primary efficacy end-point of major adverse cardiovascular event (MACE) reduction at 90 days in patients following an acute myocardial infarction (see the February 2024 issue of International Blood/Plasma News), detailed findings from the company’s Phase 3 AEGIS-II trial assessing CSL112 have been published in the New England Journal of Medicine.</p>
        <p>A total of 18,219 patients with acute myocardial infarction (AMI), multivessel coronary artery disease and additional cardiovascular risk factors were randomly assigned to receive either four weekly infusions of 6 grams of CSL112 or matching placebo, with the first infusion administered within five days after the first medical contact for the AMI.</p>
        <p>There was no significant difference between the groups in the risk of MACE (a composite of AMI, stroke or death from cardiovascular causes) at 90 days of follow-up: 439 patients (4.8%) in the CSL112 group versus 472 patients (5.2%) in the placebo group (hazard ratio, 0.93; 95% confidence interval [CI], 081 to 1.05; P= 0.24). MACE event rates at 365 days of follow-up – respectively 9.8% versus 10.5% -- were also not significantly different (hazard ratio, 0.93; 95% CI, 0.85 to 1.02). The percentage of patients with adverse events was similar between the two groups.</p>
        <p>Apolipoprotein A-I, which is the main protein in high-density lipoprotein, mediates cholesterol efflux from vascular endothelial cells. The research hypothesis that CSL112 could reduce MACE was premised on the fact that low cholesterol efflux has been associated with an increased risk of cardiovascular events.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>AKEBIA THERAPEUTICS’ VAFSEO approved for anemia in CKD patients on dialysis</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article14</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>AKEBIA THERAPEUTICS announced that the U.S. FDA has approved VAFSEO (vadadustat) tablets for the treatment of anemia due to chronic kidney disease (CKD) in adults who have been receiving dialysis for at least three months. VAFSEO is a once-daily oral hypoxia-inducible factor prolyl hydroxylase (HIF-PH) inhibitor that activates the physiologic response to hypoxia to stimulate endogenous production of erythropoietin to manage anemia.</p>
        <p>This approval is based on efficacy and safety data from the INNO2VATE program and an assessment of post-marketing safety data from Japan, where VAFSEO was launched in 2020. Results from the INNO2VATE program were published in the New England Journal of Medicine in 2021.</p>
        <p>Leveraging its established, renal-experienced commercial team and its relationship with CSL’s VIFOR PHARMA, Akebia says it will “execute a launch strategy to drive VAFSEO toward the goal of becoming a new oral standard for adult dialysis patients.” VAFSEO will compete with GSK’s JESRUVROQ (daprodustat) tablets, which in February 2023 became the first HIF-PH inhibitor to be approved for treatment of anemia caused by CKD in adults who have been on dialysis for at least four months.</p>
        <p>In 2017, Akebia granted Vifor Pharma a license to sell vadadustat to FRESENIUS MEDICAL CARE NORTH AMERICA for use solely within its U.S. network of dialysis clinics. This license was amended in 2019 to allow Vifor Pharma to additionally sell vadadustat to certain third-party dialysis organizations for use in the U.S..</p>
        <p>Approximately 500,000 U.S. adults on dialysis suffer from anemia due to CKD. Currently, most CKD patients are treated for anemia with injectable erythropoiesis-stimulating agents, usually at dialysis centers.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Study finds apheresis plasma donation not significantly associated with hemoglobin changes</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article15</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>The frequency of apheresis plasma donation is not associated with clinical meaningful changes in hemoglobin (Hb) levels, according to findings of a retrospective cohort study conducted by HémaQuébec that included donors who gave plasma at least twice between October 2020 and October 2022.</p>
        <p>A total of 9,535 men and 9,409 women made ≥2 but no more than 16 plasma donations. Over an average of 9.2 months of observation, men maintained Hb levels well above the Hb deferral threshold, decreasing only by a mean of 0.17 g/dL between the first and 15th donation return (p &lt; 0.0001).</p>
        <p>Over an average of 9.0 months of observation, women also maintained adequate Hb levels, which decreased by a mean of 0.08 g/dL between the first and 15th donation return.</p>
        <p>The investigators concluded that for donation frequencies of ≤7 to 8 times per year, this evidence that apheresis plasma donation did not meaningfully affect Hb levels raises questions about the relevance of systematically monitoring Hb in this donor population. They added, however, that “an adverse impact of plasmapheresis on Hb levels cannot be ruled out for individuals donating more frequently or for longer than about nine months”.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>HémaQuébec opens 12th plasma donor center, aims for IVIG self-sufficiency</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article16</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Separately, HémaQuébec announced that it has opened its 12th plasma donor center in Québec, and the first in the Centre-du-Québec region.</p>
        <p>The new 4,000-square foot HémaQuébec Drummondville Donor Centre is scheduled to welcome its first donors in early 2025 with the goal to collect about 12,500 donations annually for further processing into specialty drug products.</p>
        <p>While Health Canada has approved a minimum interval of every three days for apheresis plasma donation, both HémaQuébec and CANADIAN BLOOD SERVICES have elected to collect plasma at a minimum interval of every six days.</p>
        <p>“We’ve set ourselves an ambitious plan for plasma self-sufficiency, but I know we can achieve it,” said HémaQuébec president and CEO Nathalie Fagnan. “Opening a 12th donor center in Québec is in complete alignment with our mission to efficiently meet the need for blood products, particularly plasma, while increasing our independence from foreign suppliers”.</p>
        <p>Currently standing at 31%, HémaQuébec has set a goal to reach 42% self-sufficiency in intravenous immunoglobulin (IVIG) by 2026-2027. The province’s IVIG self-sufficiency level has improved from under 19% in 2019, but HémaQuébec acknowledges that “maintaining a balance between growing demand and donations remains a major challenge”.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>MiPLATE trial: Mirasol Pathogen Reduction System shows lower hemostatic function for apheresis platelets</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article17</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Using the novel endpoint of days of ≥ Grade 2 bleeding, an interim analysis of the prospective, multicenter, controlled, randomized, non-inferiority MiPLATE trial found that transfused apheresis platelets treated with TERUMO BCT’s riboflavin/UV light-based Mirasol Pathogen Reduction Technology System had lower hemostatic function than conventional apheresis platelets in patients with hypoproliferative thrombocytopenia. The Mirasol system has been used in Europe for pathogen reduction of platelets in 100% plasma since 2007.</p>
        <p>A higher percentage of subjects in the Mirasol group experienced ≥ Grade 2 bleeding for a longer period in days.</p>
        <p>Corrected count increments were also lower in the Mirasol group, while the number of platelet transfusion episodes was higher (RR = 1.22, 95% CI 1.05-1.41).</p>
        <p>However, there was no difference between Mirasol and control groups with respect to days of platelet support (RR = 0.86, 95% CI 0.68-1.08) or total number of red blood cell transfusions (RR = 1.12, 95% CI 0.91-1.37). Transfusion-emergent adverse events were also similar between groups (84.4% and 82.6% of participants, respectively).</p>
        <p>“This study did not support that Mirasol was non-inferior compared to conventional platelets using the novel endpoint [of] number of days with ≥ Grade 2 bleeding in Mirasol when compared to control,” the investigators concluded.</p>
        <p>Complete findings from this study, which was sponsored by the U.S. government’s Biomedical Advanced Research and Development Authority (BARDA), are published in the March 2024 issue of Transfusion.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>HAEMONETICS receives FDA clearance for TEG 6s hemostasis analyzer system Global Hemostasis-HN assay cartridge</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article18</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>HAEMONETICS (Boston, MA) has received 510(k) clearance from the U.S. FDA to market the TEG 6s hemostasis analyzer system Global Hemostasis-HN assay cartridge.</p>
        <p>This new cartridge extends Haemonetics’ TEG 6s viscoelastic testing capabilities to serve fully heparinized patients in adult cardiovascular surgeries/procedures and liver transplantation in both laboratory and point-of-care settings. Haemonetics said it is planning to release the new Global Hemostasis-HN cartridge for the TEG 6s system in the coming months.</p>
        <p>The company’s 510(k) clearance was supported by clinical data from a multi-center trial that included 335 patients undergoing cardiac bypass surgeries, interventional cardiology procedures or liver transplantation; an additional study conducted with 164 healthy volunteers was used to establish the normal reference ranges for the test cartridge.</p>
        <p>“TEG testing provides critical information that can help physicians improve hemostasis management for their patients, especially in critical situations like open heart and liver transplant surgeries and major trauma,” said senior vice president and chief medical officer Jan Hartmann, MD.</p>
        <p>For more information about the Haemonetics TEG 6s hemostasis analyzer system, please visit https://hospital.haemonetics.com/hemostasis-management/teg-6s.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>HemoSonics receives FDA clearance for expanded use of arterial blood samples with Quantra Qstat Cartridge</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-article19</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>HemoSonics (Durham, NC) has received Special 510(k) clearance from the U.S. FDA for the expanded use of arterial blood samples with its Quantra Qstat Cartridge used with the Quantra Hemostasis Analyzer.</p>
        <p>Hospitals can now “further standardize and operationalize viscoelastic testing with an arterial and venous indication for both HemoSonics’ QStat Cartridge and the QPlus Cartridge,” the company said.</p>
        <p>FDA-cleared for use in point-of-care settings including operating rooms, intensive care units and in hospital laboratories, the easy-to-operate Quantra System enables clinicians to deliver patient-centered decisions on bleeding management to improve care and optimize blood product usage. Comprehensive whole-blood coagulation analysis is typically completed in less than 15 minutes.</p>
        <p>A single-center report last year in the Journal of Cardiothoracic Surgery showed that implementation of the Quantra Hemostasis Analyzer with the QPlus Cartridge led to respective 97%, 67%, 26% and 10% reductions in transfused units of fresh frozen plasma, cryoprecipitate, platelets and red blood cells. These reductions in blood component usage were accompanied by a 41% overall reduction in the hospital’s cost of blood products.</p>
        <p>For more information, please visit https://hemosonics.com/quantra-hemostasis-analyzer/.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: Modified Immune Cells and Uses Thereof</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent1</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Modified Immune Cells and Uses Thereof. #11,86,731. Assigned to Chineo Medical Technology Co., Ltd. (Beijing, China). An isolated population of modified immune cells comprising modified immune cells that specifically binds to a tumor antigen, wherein each modified immune cell comprises a peripheral blood mononuclear cell (PBMC) expressing both endogenous PD1 and a chimeric stimulating molecule or a switch molecule, wherein said chimeric stimulating molecule or a switch molecule comprises:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>an extracellular domain (ECD) of a protein that, in an unmodified immune cell, elicits an immune cell inactivation signal upon binding to its ligand, wherein said ECD is fused to an intracellular domain (ICD) of a co-stimulatory molecule that mediates an immune cell activation signal,</li>
          <li>wherein binding of the chimeric stimulating molecule or the switch molecule to the ligand yields said immune cell activation signal in said modified immune cell instead of said immune cell inactivation signal, and</li>
          <li>wherein the isolated population comprises a higher concentration of PBMCs endogenously expressing PD1 compared to a population of PBMCs in a subject.</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: Monoclonal Antibodies for Human Respiratory Syncytial Virus</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent2</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Monoclonal Antibodies Specifically for the Antigen P of the Human Respiratory Syncytial Virus, Produced and Secreted by the Cells Hybridomas, Useful for Detection and Diagnostic of the Infection Caused by RSV. #11,873,331. Assigned to Pontificia Universidad Catolica de Chile (Santiago, Chile). A monoclonal antibody or a functional fragment thereof that binds to a protein P of a human Respiratory Syncytial Virus (RSV), wherein the monoclonal antibody or the functional fragment thereof comprises a heavy chain variable region and a light chain variable region, wherein the heavy chain and light chain variable regions are respectively SEQ ID No: 5 and SEQ ID No: 6.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: Prefusion RSV F Proteins and Their Use</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent3</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Prefusion RSV F Proteins and Their Use. #11,878,998. Assigned to The United States of America (Secretary, Department of Health and Human Services) (Bethesda, MD). A recombinant respiratory syncytial virus (RSV) F ectodomain trimer, comprising:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>three recombinant F2-F1 ectodomain protomers each comprising a deletion of RSV F positions 104-144 and a glycine-serine peptide linker between RSV F positions 103 and 145, wherein the recombinant F2-F1 ectodomain protomers comprise specified amino acid substitutions to stabilize the recombinant RSV F ectodomain trimer in a prefusion conformation.</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: Methods of Inactivating Viral Contaminants</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent4</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Methods of Inactivating Viral Contaminants. #11,884,700. Assigned to Ichnos Sciences SA (La Chaux-de-Fonds, Switzerland). A method for the removal of impurities from a clarified harvest antibody material, the method comprising: (a) culturing host cells which express an antibody, (b) harvesting the antibody material in the cell culture and (c) subjecting it to a clarification step, wherein said method further comprises (d) treating the resulting clarified harvest antibody material with high pH to reach a high target pH (~ 10.2 to 11) and (e) subjecting the high pH treated clarified harvest antibody material to a filtration step to remove impurities (host cell proteins, nucleic acids and/or cell debris).</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: Systems and Methods for Process Scale Isolation of Immunoglobulin G</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent5</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Systems and Methods for Process Scale Isolation of Immunoglobulin G. #11,884,702. Assigned to Plasma Technologies, LLC (Charleston, SC). A method for isolating a target protein from a solution comprising the target protein and a plurality of contaminants, comprising:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>adding a salt to the solution to generate a supernatant and a precipitate;</li>
          <li>dissolving the precipitate in an aqueous solution to generate a dissolved precipitate comprising the target protein and a first portion of the plurality of contaminants;</li>
          <li>applying the dissolved precipitate to a first ion exchange media having a first charge with a first polarity under first buffer conditions selected to not bind the target protein to generate a first bound fraction comprising a second portion of the plurality of contaminants and a first flow-through, wherein the first flow-through comprises the target protein and a third portion of the plurality of contaminants;</li>
          <li>preparing a second ion exchange media selected to bind both the target protein and a fourth portion of the plurality of contaminants under second buffer conditions, wherein the second ion exchange media comprises a second charge with a second polarity that is opposite that of the first polarity;</li>
          <li>applying the first flow-through to the second ion exchange media under second buffer conditions to generate a second bound fraction comprising the fourth portion of the plurality of contaminants and a second flow-through comprising the target protein;</li>
          <li>wherein preparing comprises selecting a limited capacity of the second exchange media such that greater than 70% of content of the target protein in the solution is recovered in the second flow-through.</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: Methods of Processing a Fluid Including a Recombinant Therapeutic Protein and Use Thereof</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent6</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Methods of Processing a Fluid Including a Recombinant Therapeutic Protein and Use Thereof. #11,884,703. Assigned to Genzyme Corporation (Cambridge, MA). A method of processing a fluid comprising a recombinant therapeutic protein, comprising:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>(a) providing a circuit system comprising (i) a tangential flow virus filtration (TFVF) unit having first and second inlets, and (ii) a conduit in fluid communication between the first and second inlets of the TFVF unit, comprising at least one port for flowing fluid into or out of, or both, of the circuit system, wherein the circuit system is configured such that fluid can be flowed through the conduit and the TFVF unit, and filtrate comprising the recombinant therapeutic protein can be collected from the TFVF unit;</li>
          <li>(b) flowing a fluid including a recombinant therapeutic protein into the circuit system through one of the at least one port, recirculating retentate in the circuit system, and</li>
          <li>collecting filtrate comprising the recombinant therapeutic protein from the TFVF unit for a period of time;</li>
          <li>wherein rate of recirculating the retentate in the circuit system and rate of flowing the fluid into the circuit system are independently controlled.</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: Potent Zika Virus-Specific and /cross-Neutralizing Monoclonal Antibodies</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent7</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Potent Zika Virus-Specific and /cross-Neutralizing Monoclonal Antibodies to Zika and Dengue Viruses Following ZIKV Infection or Vaccination. #11,884,718. Assigned to The Henry M. Jackson Foundation for the Advancement of Military Medicine, Inc. (Bethesda, MD); The Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center, Inc. (Boston, MA); and The Government of the United States as Represented by the Secretary of the Army (Fort Detrick, MD). An antibody or fragment thereof that selectively binds Zika virus.</p>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: Erythrocyte-Binding Therapeutics for Antigen-Specific Tolerance</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent8</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Erythrocyte-Binding Therapeutics. #11,884,721. Assigned to École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne (EPFL) (Lausanne, Switzerland). A method for inducing antigen-specific tolerance to an antigen in a subject, the method comprising:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>administering a composition to a subject in an amount effective to induce antigen-specific tolerance, the composition comprising:
            <ul>
              <li>i) an erythrocyte-binding moiety, which has the ability to non-covalently, specifically bind an exterior erythrocyte surface in situ in blood, wherein the erythrocyte-binding moiety comprises an antibody fragment directed against glycophorin A, and</li>
              <li>ii) an antigen to which tolerance is desired, wherein the antigen is selected from a portion of myelin basic protein, a portion of myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein, a portion of proteolipid protein, myelin basic protein, myelin oligodendrocyte glycoprotein, proteolipid protein, and combinations thereof;</li>
            </ul>
          </li>
          <li>wherein the antigen to which tolerance is desired is recombinantly fused to the erythrocyte-binding moiety, and</li>
          <li>wherein, upon administration to a human in which tolerance to the antigen is desired, the composition binds to CD45 negative cells, but not to CD45 positive cells, and the composition reduces, fails to induce, or prevents inflammatory responses in antigen-specific T cells as compared to when the human is exposed to the antigen.</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: Alpha-1 Antitrypsin (AAT) RNAi Agents and Compositions</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent9</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Alpha-1 Antitrypsin (AAT) RNAi Agents, Compositions Including AAT RNAi Agents, and Methods of Use. #11,884,920. Assigned to Arrowhead Pharmaceuticals, Inc. (Pasadena, CA). An RNAi agent for inhibiting the expression of an alpha-1 antitrypsin (AAT) gene comprising a sense strand and an antisense strand,</p>
        <ul>
          <li>wherein nucleotides 2-18 of the antisense strand are specified in the patent,</li>
          <li>wherein the sense strand is substantially complementary to the antisense strand; and</li>
          <li>wherein the antisense strand comprises (i) 2 or 3 phosphorothioate linkages at its 5′ end,</li>
          <li>(ii) at least 8 nucleotides selected from 2′-fluoro adenosine, 2′-fluoro cytidine, 2′-fluoro guanosine, and 2′-fluoro uridine, (iii) at least 11 nucleotides selected from 2′-O-methyl adenosine, 2′-O-methyl cytidine, 2′-O-methyl guanosine, and 2′-O-methyl uridine, or (iv) any combination thereof.</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Recent U.S. Patent: RNA Biomarkers for Hereditary Angioedema</title>
      <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
      <author>IBPN</author>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">ibpn-april2024-patent10</guid>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>RNA Biomarkers for Hereditary Angioedema. #11,884,979. Assigned to Takeda Pharmaceutical Company, Limited (Osaka, Japan). A method for analyzing a sample, comprising:</p>
        <ul>
          <li>(i) providing a biological sample obtained from a subject having, suspected of having, or being at risk for hereditary angioedema (HAE);</li>
          <li>(ii) measuring the level of a RNA biomarker set, wherein the RNA biomarker set comprises a messenger RNA encoding mitochondrially-encoded cytochrome C oxidase III (MT-CO3);</li>
          <li>(iii) identifying the subject as a subject having HAE based on the level of the RNA biomarker set, an increase of the level of MT-CO3 of the subject from that of a control subject being indicative of the subject having HAE; and</li>
          <li>(iv) administering to the subject identified as having HAE in step (iii) an effective amount of a therapeutic agent for treating HAE;</li>
          <li>wherein the therapeutic agent is a plasma kallikrein (pKal) inhibitor, a bradykinin 2 receptor (B2R) inhibitor, and/or a Cl esterase inhibitor.</li>
        </ul>
      ]]></description>
      <source url="http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com">IBPN</source>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>