<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>International Blood/Plasma News - June 2019</title>
    <link>http://www.marketingresearchbureau.com</link>
    <description>RSS feed generated from IBPN June 2019 issue</description>
    <language>en-us</language>

    <item>
      <title>Grifols and Ethicon introduce VISTASEAL/VERASEAL fibrin sealant</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>GRIFOLS announced that, in a first-time broad global relationship with ETHICON to provide plasma protein-based solutions to manage surgical bleeding, it will introduce a new fibrin sealant product to be brand named VISTASEAL in the U.S. and VERASEAL in other select markets. The Grifols-developed product, which combines human plasma-derived fibrinogen and thrombin, will be commercially launched in the second half of 2019. It is administered with Ethicon’s airless spray device technology.</p>
        <p>The alliance also anticipates pairing Grifols’ lyophilized human thrombin with Ethicon’s currently available SURGIFLO Hemostatic Matrix to provide surgeons with more advanced options to facilitate and induce clotting during surgery.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Versiti rebrands regional blood centers and opens new Ohio center</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>The U.S. non-profit blood and related blood services provider VERSITI announced that it is transitioning its four Midwest blood centers to a single unified Versiti brand this year.</p>
        <p>Indiana Blood Center → Versiti Blood Center of Indiana<br/>
        Heartland Blood Centers → Versiti Blood Center of Illinois<br/>
        Michigan Blood → Versiti Blood Center of Michigan<br/>
        BloodCenter of Wisconsin → Versiti Blood Center of Wisconsin</p>
        <p>In addition, Versiti is establishing a fifth blood center – Versiti Blood Center of Ohio – to serve the Ohio State Wexner Medical Center; this new Columbus, Ohio-based blood center is set to open on July 1, replacing blood and specialty laboratory services previously provided by the AMERICAN RED CROSS.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>CMS issues preliminary recommendation for new billing code for blood products</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Responding to a joint letter and formal request from AABB, the AMERICAN RED CROSS and AMERICA’S BLOOD CENTERS, the U.S. Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services (CMS) has issued a preliminary recommendation to establish a new “not otherwise classified” (NOC) HCPCS Level II billing code that U.S. hospitals can use to bill insurers and secure reimbursement for new types of transfused blood products prior to the creation of a permanent HCPCS billing code.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Japan MHLW publishes 2019 plan for plasma-derived and recombinant products</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Japan’s Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare (MHLW) has recently published its 2019 plan for the domestic production and import of plasma-derived and recombinant medicinal products.</p>
        <p>Albumin: 31,508 kg demand<br/>Factor VIII: 842,800,000 IU demand<br/>Factor IX: 139,600,000 IU demand<br/>IVIG/SCIG: 6,290 kg demand</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Genentech/Roche’s HEMLIBRA gains share in hemophilia A market</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>In the first quarter of 2019, an estimated 8% of all U.S. hemophilia A patients on treatment, and significantly more of those specifically on prophylaxis, used GENENTECH/ROCHE’S HEMLIBRA, according to The Marketing Research Bureau’s newly released report titled Hemophilia Care & Price Monitoring, Wave #26.</p>
        <p>HEMLIBRA dominated the inhibitor market, capturing the majority of hemophilia A patients with inhibitors, with a corresponding reduction in Takeda’s FEIBA, Novo Nordisk’s NovoSeven and immune tolerance induction (ITI) treatments.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Fresenius Kabi receives FDA clearance for ALYX Component Collection System</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>FRESENIUS KABI USA has received U.S. FDA 510(k) clearance to market its ALYX Component Collection System for use in the collection of multiple blood components, including leukocyte-reduced red blood cells, plasma, and source plasma.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Erytech Pharma gains FDA IND acceptance for eryaspase in pancreatic cancer trial</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>The French clinical-stage biopharmaceutical firm ERYTECH Pharma announced that the U.S. FDA has accepted its Investigational New Drug (IND) application for eryaspase – the enzyme L-asparaginase encapsulated inside donor-derived red blood cells – enabling U.S. patient enrollment in its ongoing Phase 3 TRYbeCA trial for pancreatic cancer.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Alexion’s ULTOMIRIS approved in Japan for PNH</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Japan’s Ministry of Health, Labour and Welfare (MHLW) has approved ALEXION PHARMACEUTICALS’ novel long-acting C5 complement inhibitor ULTOMIRIS (ravulizumab) for the treatment of adult patients with paroxysmal nocturnal hemoglobinuria (PNH). Administered intravenously every eight weeks, ULTOMIRIS was first approved in the U.S. for PNH in December 2018.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>BioMarin reports 3-year update on hemophilia A gene therapy valoctocogene roxaparvovec</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>In a three-year update to results of its investigational gene therapy treatment for adults with severe hemophilia A, BioMarin Pharmaceutical reported that bleed rate control with valocotogene roxaparvovec 6e13 vg/kg dose was maintained for a third year, with a median annualized bleed rate of zero.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>bluebird bio’s ZYNTEGLO gene therapy receives conditional EU approval</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>The European Commission has granted conditional marketing authorization for bluebird bio’s ZYNTEGLO, a gene therapy for patients aged 12+ with transfusion-dependent β-thalassemia who lack a matched donor for transplantation. ZYNTEGLO is a single-administration therapy offering the potential for life-long transfusion independence.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Global Blood Therapeutics’ voxelotor shows Phase 3 success in sickle cell disease</title>
      <description><![CDATA[
        <p>Oral administration of GLOBAL BLOOD THERAPEUTICS’ sickle hemoglobin polymerization inhibitor voxelotor significantly increased hemoglobin levels and reduced markers of hemolysis in patients with sickle cell disease, according to Phase 3 HOPE trial results.</p>
      ]]></description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
